Inventory of the Vic and Barby Ulmer collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Sustainability, 1997-2007, undated (Boxes 24-26)
  - Habitat for Humanity (Africa), 2002 (Box-folder 25: 7)
  - Health, 2002-2005 (Box-folder 25: 8)
  - Investing in development, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 25: 9)
  - Microlending, 2006 (Box-folder 25: 10)
  - Oil 2005-2050 [projections], 2004-2006 (Box-folder 25: 11)
  - Solar cooking, 1999-2007 (Box-folder 25: 12)
  - Sustainable development, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 25: 13-14)
  - Transportation, 2004 (Box-folder 25: 15)
  - Vegetarians, undated (Box-folder 25: 16)
  - Wind power, 2006 (Box-folder 26: 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 2006, undated (Box-folder 26: 2)
- South Africa, 1976-2005, undated (Boxes 26-27)
  See also: boxes 2-6, 10-11, 17-19, 29-30, 32-35, and 37-39.
  - Action and resources, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 26: 3)
  - Children, 2002-2005 (Box-folder 26: 4)
  - Children and religion, 2001-2005 (Box-folder 26: 5)
  - HIV/AIDS publications, 2002 (Box-folder 26: 6)
  - Kids' drawings, 5-12, undated (Box-folder 26: 7)
  - Land, 1989 (Box-folder 26: 8)
  - Molo Songololo, 1991-2005 (Box-folder 26: 9)
    Contains copies of a South African children's magazine.
  - Moral Regeneration Movement (MRM), 2004 (Box-folder 26: 10)
  - Newspapers, 2005 (Box-folder 26: 11)
  - Slide shows, 1976-1994 (Box-folder 26: 12-14)
  - South Africa Now, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 26: 15)
    Material about the weekly news program.
  - Soweto video, 2002 (Box-folder 27: 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1983-1998 (Box-folder 27: 2-3)
- Africa, 1974-2009, undated (Boxes 27-32)
  See also: boxes 1-2, 12, 20, 33-34, 37, and 39.
  - Africa Today: An Atlas of Reproducible Pages, 1983 (Box-folder 27: 4)
  - Children and women, 1982-2005 (Box-folder 27: 5)
  - "A Glance of Southern Africa: A Collection of Essays,", undated (Box-folder 27: 6)
  - Government, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 27: 7)
  - Hunger, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 27: 8)
  - Information resources, 1978-1992 (Box-folder 27: 9-10, Box-folder 28: 1)
  - Kenya, 1974-1995 (Box-folder 28: 2)
    See also: boxes 1 and 12.
  - Mali, 1976-1987 (Box-folder 28: 3)
  - Namibia, 1980-1993 (Box-folder 28: 4-9)
  - Notebooks, 1993 (Box-folder 28: 10)
  - Our Developing World newsletters, 1995-2009 (Box-folder 28: 11)
    See also: box 2.
  - Peacenet, 1995 (Box-folder 28: 12)
  - "The Samo of Upper Volta: A People in West Africa,", 1973 (Box-folder 28: 13)
  - Southern Africa, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 28: 14)
  - Statistics by country, 1975 (Box-folder 28: 15)
  - Tanzania, 1977-1984, undated (Box-folder 29: 1-2)
    See also: boxes 1-2, 13, and 35-36.
  - Teaching materials, 1976-2007, undated
    - Lesson plans for 6-12 year olds, 1979-1985 (Box-folder 29: 3)
    - Match and name game, undated (Box-folder 29: 4)
    - Our Developing World teaching kit, 1989, undated (Box-folder 29: 5)
    - South Africa, 1976-1998 (Box-folder 29: 6-9, Box-folder 30: 1-6)
    - Southern Africa, 1983-2007 (Box-folder 30: 7)
    - Teaching French, 2000 (Box-folder 30: 8)
    - Teachings, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 31: 1)
    - Zimbabwe, 1984-2000, undated (Box-folder 31: 2-11)
  - "These People Cannot Wait: The Special 'Ring' Campaign for Africa,", 1985 (Box-folder 31: 12)
  - West Africa, 1990 (Box-folder 31: 13)
  - Women, undated (Box-folder 31: 14)
  - World Neighbors, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 31: 15)
  - Zimbabwe: Ephemera and printed matter, 1980-1990 (Box-folder 32: 1-2)
- 2012 increment, 1975-2009, undated (Boxes 32-33)
  - South Africa, 1989-2009, undated
    See also: boxes 2-6, 10-11, 17-19, 26-27, 29-30, 34-35, and 37-39.
    - Acronyms, 1996 (Box-folder 32: 3)
    - Affirmative action, 1996 (Box-folder 32: 4)
    - African Growth and Opportunity Act (AGOA), 2004 (Box-folder 32: 5)
    - Afrikaners, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 32: 6)
    - Aid, 1995 (Box-folder 32: 7)
    - AIDS education, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 32: 8)
    - Alexandra Health Centre & University Clinic, annual report, 2001 (Box-folder 32: 9)
    - Apartheid's scars, 1994 (Box-folder 32: 10)
    - Bibliography, 1997 (Box-folder 32: 11)
    - Constitution Hill, 2002 (Box-folder 32: 12)
    - Disability workshops, 2007 (Box-folder 32: 13)
    - Drama, 2005 (Box-folder 32: 14)
    - Ecology, 1992-2003 (Box-folder 32: 15)
    - Environment, 1998-2002 (Box-folder 32: 16)
    - Fishing/fisherpeople, 2002 (Box-folder 32: 17)
    - Freedom Charter, 2004 (Box-folder 32: 18)
    - Gender Commission, 1991, undated (Box-folder 32: 19)
    - Geographic facts, 1994-1998 (Box-folder 32: 20)
    - "Good News,", 2004 (Box-folder 32: 21)
    - Gun control, 1999 (Box-folder 32: 22)
    - Home of Hope, 1996-2002 (Box-folder 32: 23)
    - Human Rights Commission, 1991-2000 (Box-folder 32: 24)
    - Information packet, 1993-2009 (Box-folder 33: 1)
      Includes a report on South Africa written by Vic and Barby Ulmer.
    - Judiciary, 2002 (Box-folder 33: 2)
    - Kliptown, 2002 (Box-folder 33: 3)
    - Lapsley, Michael, 2004 (Box-folder 33: 4)
    - Maps, 1989, undated (Box-folder 33: 5)
    - Marcus, Gill, 2009 (Box-folder 33: 6)
    - Mbeki, Thabo, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 33: 7)
    - Naledi Doll Project, undated (Box-folder 33: 8)
    - "Nkosi Sikeleli Afrika" (Lord Bless Africa), 1993 (Box-folder 33: 9)
    - Periodicals, 2002-2009 (Box-folder 33: 10)
    - Poverty, 2002 (Box-folder 33: 11)
    - Privatisation, 2004 (Box-folder 33: 12)
    - Quakers, Gun Free South Africa, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 33: 13)
    - Racism, South Africa and the United States, 2001 (Box-folder 33: 14)
    - Robben Island, 2002 (Box-folder 33: 15)
    - South Africa update, 2000-2004 (Box-folder 33: 16)
    - Theatre, 1994-1999 (Box-folder 33: 17)
    - Trauma counseling, 1998 (Box-folder 33: 18)
    - Trust for Community Outreach and Education annual report, 2008 (Box-folder 33: 19)
    - Violence, 1994 (Box-folder 33: 20)
    - Visuals, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 33: 21)
  - Africa, 1975-2008, undated
    See also: boxes 1-2, 12, 20, 27-32, and 37-39.
    - Call to Conscience Network sign, undated (Box-folder 33: 22)
    - Namibia, 2001 (Box-folder 34: 1)
    - Rwanda, 1998 (Box-folder 34: 2)
    - Sudan, 2000-2008 (Box-folder 34: 3)
    - Visuals, 1975-2001 (Box-folder 34: 4)
    - Zimbabwe, 1983-2008 (Box-folder 34: 5)
  - Soviet Union, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 34: 6)
- Photographs, 1976-2006 (Boxes 34-36)
  - South Africa and Namibia album, 1993 (Box-folder 34: 7-9)
  - Slides, 1976-2006
    - Mozambique, 1984-1990 (Box-folder 34: 10-12)
    - Nairobi, 1976-1985 (Box-folder 34: 13)
    - Namibia, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 34: 14, Box-folder 35: 1)
    - Namibia/Mozambique, 1991 (Box-folder 35: 2)
    - South Africa, 1986-2006 (Box-folder 35: 3-12)
    - South Africa and South East Asia, 1999 (Box-folder 35: 13)
    - Tanzania, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 35: 14, Box-folder 36: 1-6)
      See also: boxes 1-2, 13, and 29.
    - Tanzania self reliance and appropriate technology, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 36: 7)
    - Zimbabwe, 1980-1990 (Box-folder 36: 8-10)
- Audiovisual material, 1983-2002, undated (Boxes 37-39)
  - Compact sound cassettes, 1984-2002, undated (Boxes 37-38)
    - African National Congress (ANC) cassettes, 1988-1992
      - "ANC Chaplain, Interview with Studs Terkel,", 1991 (Box 37)
      - "ANC - Pallo Jordan,", 1988
      - "ANC and South Africa,", 1990
      - "ANC and Walter Turner,", 1992
    - "Afrikaner Journalist,", 1990
    - "Angola" and "Mozambique,", undated
    - "Celebration Evening Hiekwene Center" and "ORAP - Bulawayo,", 1984
    - "Children of Angola,", 1988
    - "Hunger in Africa" and "Balancing a Chemical Equation,", 1984
    - "Kingdoms and Empires in Tropical Africa (Before 1500 AD),", 1970
    - Mandela, Nelson cassettes, 1988-1997, undated
      - "Mandela and Botha" and "Cooking and Heating in Biogas (India),", 1988
      - "Mandela Film,", 1997
      - "Mandela: Making a Film about Him,", undated
      - "Nelson Mandela," 2 cassettes, 1989
    - Mozambique cassettes, 1984-1990, undated
      - "Graca Machel,", 1989
      - "Immigrant Labor in Mozambique,", 1988
      - "Mozambique," "Mozambique's Children," and "Schools in South Africa,", 1990
      - "Mozambique Ending with OMM COOP," and "Mozambique - Kindergarten Ending w/ V. Min. Foreign Affairs Daniel Mboza,", undated
      - "Mozambique School – Isle of Youth,", undated
      - "Mozambique Update,", 1988
      - "Prexy Nesbitt - Mozambique" and "Prexy Nesbitt - Kevin Danaher: South Africa and Mozambique,", 1989
      - "Stephanie Urdang: Mozambican Women,", 1984
    - Namibia cassettes, 1989
      - "Namibia Elections CBC" and "South Africa and Mozambique, Kevin Danaher and Walter Turner,", 1989
      - "Namibia Faces Elections,", 1989
    - South Africa cassettes, 1987-2002, undated
      - "Community Schools Access in South Africa,", 1999
      - "Desmond Tutu (Nat’l Press Club)" and "Filipino Trade Unions and Agrarian Reform,", 1988
      - "Donald Woods: Apartheid and Sanctions,", 1989
      - "Farid Esack - South African Muslim Theologian," "Just War, Just Peace," and "Update on TRC,", 2001
      - "Fault Lines: Journey Into the New South Africa - David Goodman, Michael Lapsley,", 1999
      - "Music from South Africa," and "Readings: Nelson Mandela Trial,", 1989
      - "One Year of Freedom, CBC,", 2000
      - "Rebuilding South Africa," Common Ground, 1999 March 2
      - "Sadec and South Africa,", 1993
      - "Steve Biko Biography" and "South African Domestics,", 1987
      - "Steve Biko Inquest, Part 2,", undated
      - "South Africa: Cities of Gold,", 2001
      - "South Africa: Dr. Mofundu Walaza, Trauma Center for Survivors,", 2002
      - "South Africa Elections: Rachel Richman and Pearl A. March,", 1993 (Box 38)
      - "South Africa: Housing,", 1996
      - "South Africa Post 1999 Election (Democracy Now),"
      - "South Africa: Rehama,", 2000
      - "South Africa: Reporting About,", 1991
      - "South Africa/Robert Price UC Berkeley,", 1999
      - "South Africa Today: Pallo Jordan,", 1988
      - "South Africa Update: Mushiwe Jenkins - Sister City Project,", 1994
      - "South Africa's State of Emergency and News Coverage CBC" and "Saturday Night at the Palace,", 1988
      - "Walter Turner and South Africa," "South Africa," "Terre'Blanche Sparks," and "Effects of [F. W.] de Klerk D.C. Visit,", 1990
    - Trade and globalization cassettes, 2002-2003, undated
      - "2 Globalizations: Kevin Danahur" and "Helen Caldecot: Nuclear Nightmare,", 2003
      - "Alternatives to Economic Globalization,", 2002
      - "NAFTA,", undated
      - "WTO Debate,", undated
    - "Truth and Reconciliation Commission," 3 cassettes, 1996, undated
    - "Zimbabwe Women’s Conference,", 1988
  - VHS videocassettes, 1983-2002, undated (Box 39)
    - "A.F.R.I.C.A" by Stetsasonic, 1988 April 27
    - Africa: Geography, undated
    - Apartheid: A History, undated
    - Apartheid Survivor: Father Michael Lapsley Speaks About Truth and Reconciliation in South Africa, undated
    - "Discussion Following 'The Day After,'", 1983 November 20
    - "Fear and Favor in Newsroom," "Amy Biehl Story," and "Road to Riches,", undated
    - "Mandela’s Fight for Freedom" and "Aftermath of Apartheid,", undated
    - "Mandela Interview," "Long Walk of Nelson Mandela," and "Rwanda: Sometimes in April,", 1990, 1999, undated
    - "Masai: Art and Culture," "Bishop Kelly," "Mystery of the Senses: Smell," and "Warrior Marks,", 1993, 1995, undated
    - "Sahel Love Story," Africa, undated
    - "South Africa: Gold Mining," "The Road to Timbuktu," and "Lost Cities of the South,", 2001, undated
    - "South Africa: Under the Gun," "Search for Sandra Laing," "Collage of South African History," and "Choosing for Justice - Nadine Gordimer,", undated
    - South Africa Now, circa 1996
    - Soweto Unveiled, 2002
    - Tears of Blood, undated
    - "TRC [Truth and Reconciliation Commission] '96," short version, 1997
    - "Truth Commission," master, undated
    - "Truth and Reconciliation Commission, South Africa, Hearings and Process,", undated
    - Two Trevors Go to Washington, 2000
    - Voices from South Africa, 2 videocassettes, 1988
      Tape 1 contains "Part I: The Art of Liberation" and "Part II: Isilelo (Funeral)." Tape 2 contains "Part III: The Story of Sicelo Dhlomo," "Part IV: Banned!," and "Part V: Dr. Ivan Toms."
    - "Witness to Apartheid," "It’s Up to Us," and "Cry of Reason,", 1986-1988
- Oversize material, 1975-2003, undated (Map case)
  Contains posters, flyers, and other ephemera.
  - Africa, 1986-1996, undated (Folder 1-2)
    Contains material related to women, voting, and other social and political issues in Africa, especially in South Africa. Contains some material in Swahili.
  - Central America and Cuba, 1981-2003, undated (Folder 3)
    Includes material from Guatemala, Nicaragua, and Honduras. Material is in Spanish and indigenous languages.
  - China and Mongolia, 1975-1982, undated (Folder 4-5)